# **Leonid Petrov**

.NET Software engineer

#### About

Antalya TR

□ ungerfall@gmail.com

leonid-petrov-803808195

Ungerfall

#### Back-end

#### Advanced

.NET C# MSSQL

ASP.NET Core Azure

Azure Cosmos DB

# DevOps

#### Novice

Azure GCP AWS

GitLab

## Front-end

#### Novice

React JS TypeScript

# Leadership & Soft Skills

## **Advanced**

**Developing Others** 

Mentoring

# **Giving Feedback**

# Languages

English (B2) Russian (Native)

# Interests

# Chess

# **Bicycle**

# Summary

Software Engineer with over 8 years of professional experience specializing in .NET, MS SQL RDBMS, and Azure cloud services. Developing, deploying, and maintaining production-level applications using ReactJS. Skilled in mentoring junior to mid-level engineers and well-versed in both Iterative Waterfall and Agile project management methodologies.

# Experience

Senior software engineer

Data transfer system of an alternative investment platform

- Fixed and improved integration tests during project onboarding
- Helped to onboard two developers
- Improved observability of the data transfer system using observable monitoring and notifications
- Migrated net48 and netcore3.1 to net6.0 target framework

06/2023 - 10/2023

06/2022 - Present

# Build engineer

New AI assisted (Open AI API: chatgpt and vectorization) system for e-commerce sites research

01/2022 - 06/2022

Senior software engineer

A key developer for a new cloud native educational platform to integrate internal and external systems

- Azure (Cosmos DB, Functions, Logic Apps), .net 6, ReactJS
- Developed and designed React application
- Developed and designed ASP.NET Core WebApi
- Developed data access layer for CosmosDB

01/2021 - 01/2022

#### Software engineer

New system to automate loan usage monitoring

- ASP.NET Core, EF Core, MassTransit, OData, SignalR
- Designed database structure for the main business processes (Funds transfer, Credit products repayment)
- Developed several HTTP services using ASP.NET Core with OData support for filtering and pagination
- Developed Notification Hub Web API using SignalR

12/2017 - 01/2021

#### Software engineer

A large and complex securities operations back-office system

- MSSQL, .NET Framework, RDLC reports
- Enhanced personal income taxes calculation system with new business rules, law amendments
- Maintained integration service
- Developed RDLC and XSLT reports
- Optimized SQL stored procedures

09/2016 - 12/2017

#### Junior software engineer

Request and storage of credit score information in a banking system

- .NET Framework, MSSQL, WCF
- Developed an adapter for a 3rd-party API
- Developed WCF service contracts
- Maintained stored procedures and unit tests

# Education

# Kalashnikov Izhevsk State Technical University

Bachelor Software Engineering

# Volunteer

#### **EPAM** eKids

Teacher

The Introduction to Programming with Scratch, a block-based visual programming language devicourse aims to cultivate logical reasoning, problem-solving skills, and an understanding of complete control of the control

- Awarded 'EPAM eKids Guru'
- Developed chess game viewer in Scratch https://github.com/Ungerfall/learning-scratch/t

# References

Leonid joint the project and quickly learned the technology stack we were using. During his partic great quality code, fully tested and even provided feedback about the requirements and possible it imezone, but he managed to stay after his working hours to overlay customers timezone and provanice person and a great team member which always provided good feedback on peer's code and members.

Thiago Fernandes Custodi

Throughout the work on the project I was repeatedly convinced that Leonid has a well-developed perfectly understood the root cause of a problem and could effectively solve it. Moreover, the solu crutches. In one case, the proposed and implemented solution was highly versatile that we started modules. Ultimately, this allowed us to reduce amount of code and improve maintainability.

- Aibulat Ak

Leonid is a competent full stack developer. With deep knowledge in databases and clouds (AZURE excellent feedbacks from projects and certificates. In addition to project activities, py proved hims 5 different mentoring programs) and community speaker (5 times), participated in project intervie

- Alexandr Usynir